# Jiasheng Gu

Homepage GitHub LinkedIn Email: gujiashe@usc.edu Phone: +1 (213) 204-0294

Research Interests

My research interest lies in the fields of natural language processing and generation, along with reliable and efficient methods for interconverting between natural language and different forms of data.

**Long-term research goal:** Use artificial intelligence to turn natural language into a bridge to various tasks.

Education

#### University of Southern California

Los Angeles, CA

M.S. in Machine Learning and Data Science Aug. 2021 - May. 2023 Relevant Courses: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Probability, Linear Algebra *GPA*: 4.0/4.0 (100%)

# **Xidian University**

Xian, Shaanxi

B.E. in Telecommunications Engineering Sep. 2017 - Jun. 2021

GPA: 3.6/4.0 (90%, Top 10%)

#### **Publications**

# Co-evolving Data-driven and NLU-driven Synthesizers for Generating Code in Domain Growth and Data Scarcity

**Jiasheng Gu**, Zifan Nan, Zhiyuan Peng, Dongkuan Xu, Xipeng shen *Submitted, ACL* 

#### Robustness of learning from task instructions

**Jiasheng Gu**, Hongyu Zhao, Hanzi Xu, Liangyu Nie, Hongyuan Mei, Wenpeng Yin *Arxiv*, Submitted, ACL

#### The Evolution of Artificial Intelligence in Bio-Medicine

Jiasheng Gu, Lili Wang, Soroush Vosoughi

Submitted, Journal of Medical Internet Research (JMIR)

#### Research Experience

#### **North Carolina State University**

• Mentors: Dongkuan Xu, Xipeng Shen

- Aug. 2022 Present
- Project: Zero-shot Code Generation via Rule-AI Co-learning from Document
- Contribution: Proposed a zero-shot code generation framework combining rule-based and AI-based methods to generate DSL code.
- Publication: ACL in prep

#### University of Southern California

• Mentors: Peter A. Beerel

- Aug. 2022 Present
- Project: Designing visual networks with very low FLOPs
- Contribution: Proposed a dilated depthwise convolution that captures global information and extensive experiments are done on it.

#### Pennsylvania State University

• Mentor: Wenpeng Yin June. 2022 - Oct. 2022

• Project: Robustness of learning from task instructions

• Contribution: Experimented and analyzed the robustness of the instruction-tuned model on perturbed instructions.

• Publication: *Arxiv* 

#### **Dartmouth College**

• Mentor: Soroush Vosoughi

May. 2022 - Sep. 2022

• Project: The Evolution of Artificial Intelligence in Bio-Medicine

• Contribution: Proposed a method to analyze artificial intelligence techniques used in biomedical publications.

• Publication: JMIR submitted

#### University of Southern California

· Mentor: Pedro Szekely

Jan. 2022 - May. 2022

- Project: Integrating factual information from language models into knowledge graph embeddings
- Contribution: Improved link prediction task by factual information mined from language models via prompts.

# University of Southern California

• Mentor: Massoud Pedram

Aug. 2021 - Dec. 2021

- Project: Reduced-Memory-Access Inference of Deep Neural Networks
- Contribution: Integrated PyTorch distributed data-parallel framework into the flow to support multi-GPU processing.

#### ETH Zürich

• Mentor: Yuyi Wang

June. 2020 - Oct. 2020

- Project: Designing pre-training tasks for text summarization
- Contribution: Using trained metrics to find the highest importance sentences as summaries makes the pre-training task more effective.

# **Industry Experience**

#### Lime

SDE internship

May. 2022 - Aug. 2022

• Reengineered a system for extracting and computing features to make it easier to modify feature definitions and compute features more efficiently.

#### **Umer Technology**

• NLP internship

Apr. 2021 - Aug. 2021

• Deployed a medical named entity identification system via BERT+CRF.

#### **Transwarp**

· NLP internship

Jan. 2021 - Apr. 2021

• Established a text summarization system with an extractive-abstractive structure.

### Professional service

#### **Program Committee**

• The European Chapter of the ACL (EACL)

2023

• ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining(WSDM)

2023

Teaching Experience	<ul> <li>Teaching assistant, University of Southern California</li> <li>EE 503: Probability for Electrical and Computer Engineers</li> <li>Grading course work and answering questions for students.</li> </ul>	Fall 2022
Awards	<ul><li>Master of Science (M.S.)</li><li>Masters Students Honors Program (USC)</li></ul>	2021
	<ul> <li>Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.)</li> <li>ZTE Algorithm Competition, Regional Winner Award</li> <li>Third Class Scholarship (Xidian University)</li> </ul>	2020 2019
Skills	Programming Python, C++, C, R, Java, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, MATLAB Framework	

PyTorch, Tensorflow, OpenCV, NumPy, Scikit-Learn, SciPy

Git, LaTeX, SPSS, Mathematica, AWS, GCP, Docker, MongoDB

# References Filip Ilievski, Assistant Professor

Viterbi School of Engineering University of Southern California ilievski@isi.edu

# Peter A. Beerel, Professor

**Professional Softwares** 

Ming Hsieh Electrical and Computer Engineering Department University of Southern California pabeerel@usc.edu

### Soroush Vosoughi, Assistant Professor

Department of Computer Science Dartmouth College soroush.vosoughi@dartmouth.edu

# Wenpeng Yin, Assistant Professor

Computer Science and Engineering Department Pennsylvania State University wenpeng.yin@temple.edu

# Dongkuan Xu, Assistant Professor

Department of Computer Science North Carolina State University dxu27@ncsu.edu

# Xipeng Shen, Professor

Department of Computer Science North Carolina State University xshen5@ncsu.edu